Guide to the Beinecke Family Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
Beinecke family papers
1786-1980
GEN MSS 570
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
43.71
(30 boxes)
The Beinecke Family Papers consist of twenty-one albums containing manuscript and printed materials, photographs, and original documents detailing the history of Edwin J. Beinecke and his family, the Weigle and Mauer families, the Sperry and Hutchinson Company, and the Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library. Materials contained within the albums date from the eighteenth century to 1980. These volumes were compiled by Fred L. Mayer between 1972 and 1980. Also included are eight volumes of letters and cards of condolence on the occasion of Edwin J. Beinecke's death in 1970. One box of miscellaneous print, typescript, and manuscript materials is also included.
Beinecke family
Mayer, Fred L.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift of Mrs. Edwin J. Beinecke, 1983.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Scope and Contents
The Beinecke Family Papers consist of twenty-one albums containing manuscript and printed materials, photographs, and original documents detailing the history of Edwin J. Beinecke and his family, the Weigle and Mauer families, the Sperry and Hutchinson Company, and the Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library. Materials contained within the albums span from the eighteenth century to 1980. These volumes were compiled by Fred L. Mayer between 1972 and 1980. Also included are eight volumes of letters and cards of condolence on the occasion of Edwin J. Beinecke's death in 1970. One box of miscellaneous print, typescript, and manuscript materials is also included.
Arrangement
The Beinecke Family papers are organized into three series, Family History Albums, Correspondence on the Passing of Edwin John Beinecke, and Other Papers.
Albums (Books); Photographs; Beinecke, Edwin J. (Edwin John), 1886-1970; Beinecke family; Mauer family; Weigle family; Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library; Sperry and Hutchinson Company
- Family History Albums, 1786-[1980]; Series I; 31.5; (21 boxes)
  Scope and Contents
  This series contains twenty-one scrapbooks documenting the history of the Beinecke, Weigle, and Mauer families, the Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library, and the Sperry and Hutchinson Company.
  - The Weigle Family in Germany, 1600-1854 with the pictorial background of their home towns. The Weigle Family in the United States, 1854-1870 with the pictorial background of Old New York., 1793-1973 (Box 1)
  - The Weigle Family in Old New York, 1870-1894., 1864-1973 (Box 2)
  - The Bernhard Beinecke Story, 1877-1890., 1862-1973 (Box 3)
  - The Bernhard Beinecke Story, 1890-1907. The Old and the New Plaza Hotel., 1886-1979 (Box 4)
  - The Bernard Beinecke Story, 1915-1932. Edwin J. Beinecke Sr. Captain, Quartermaster Corps, 1918-1919., 1905-[1980] (Box 5)
  - Edwin J. Beinecke's School Years, The first pay check, The Beinecke/Mauer Merger, Family Life, 1897-1917., 1897-[1980] (Box 6)
  - Edwin J. Beinecke Sr. the new president of the Sperry & Hutchinson Co., 1922-1928., 1899-[1980] (Box 7)
  - Edwin J. Beinecke, 1928-1941, 1929-[1980] (Box 8)
  - Skerryvore, the home of Edwin & Linda Beincke. The Rhododendron, Azelea & Narcissi Gardens. The Lighthouse. Robert Louis Stevenson memorabilia., 1874-[1980] (Box 9)
  - Edwin J. Beinecke, 1948-1959, 1941-[1980] (Box 10)
  - Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library, 1786-[1980] (Box 11)
  - Edwin J. Beinecke. 1960 - January 21, 1970, 1954-[1980] (Box 12)
  - Henry Mauer Family, 1858-[1980] (Box 13)
  - History of The Sperry & Hutchinson Co., part 1, 1897-[1980] (Box 14)
  - The Sperry & Hutchinson Co., part 2, 1905-[1980] (Box 15)
  - The Sperry & Hutchinson Co., part 3, 1963-[1980] (Box 16)
  - Edwin J. Beinecke, Jr., 1914-1936, 1915-[1980] (Box 17)
  - Edwin J. Beinecke, Jr., 1941-1965, 1940-[1980] (Box 18)
  - Edwin J. Beinecke, Jr., 1966-1971, 1966-[1980] (Box 19)
  - The Homes in Remsenburg, 1893-[1980] (Box 20)
  - Edwin J. Beinecke, Jr., 1976-1979, 1969-[1980] (Box 21)
- Correspondence on the Passing of Edwin John Beinecke, 1970; Series II; 12; (8 boxes)
  Arrangement
  The correspondence within the scrapbooks is arranged alphabetically.
  This series consists of eight scrapbooks filled with letters and cards of condolence on the occasion of Edwin J. Beinecke's death in 1970.
  - A-B, 1970 (Box 22)
  - C-E, 1970 (Box 23)
  - F-G, 1970 (Box 24)
  - H-K, 1970 (Box 25)
  - L-M, 1970 (Box 26)
  - N-R, 1970 (Box 27)
  - S-T, 1970 (Box 28)
  - U-Z, 1970 (Box 29)
- Other Papers, Series III; 0.21; (1 box)
  - Correspondence, 1903-51, undated (Box 30, Folder 1)
  - Miscellaneous typescript and manuscript pages, 1951, undated (Box 30, Folder 2)
  - Clippings, undated (Box 30, Folder 3)
  - Photograph of a duck, undated (Box 30, Folder 4)
  - Printed ephemera, undated (Box 30, Folder 5)